Joseph Pitts

PERSONAL INFORMATION

ADDRESS ONE: 29 Hewson Road, Lincoln, LN1 1RZ

ADDRESS TWO: 134 Leeds Road, Allerton Bywater, Yorkshire, WF10 2HB

PHONE: +07 936 050206
EMAIL ONE: joepittsy@gmail.com

EMAIL TWO: 16657094@students.lincoln.ac.uk

ABOUT

I am a Computer Science undergraduate at the University of Lincoln. I have been studying Computer Science for over 6 years at GCSE, A-Level and now degree. However I have been interested in the field much longer then that. I am a hardworking individual with strong technical skills and work well both alone and as part of a team.

EDUCATION

LDOC/(ITON			
2018 - Present	BSC COMPUTER SCIENCE, The University of Lincoln		
	1st Year Grade: 1st		
	Module	Grade	
	Programming & Data Structures	1st	
	Maths for Computing	1st	
	Operating Systems	2:1	
	Algorithms & Complexity	1st	
	Problem Solving	2:2	
	Computer Architectures	1st	
	Web Authoring	1st	
	G		
2016 - 2018	A LEVELS, New College Pontefract		
	Subject Grade		
	Maths B		
	Business B		
	Computer Science C		
	·		
2012 - 2016	GCSE, Brigshaw High School & Language College		
	10 GCSES including A's in Maths, C	omputer Science & Physics and a B	
	in English	,	

EXPERIENCE

NOVEMBER 2018	Partook in the Sir William Siemens Challenge Worked with a team of 6 others over a period of 3 days to build a device that visualised data in new and innovative ways.
2017 - 2018	Crew Member at McDonalds Maintained high standards of customer service during high-volume, fast-paced operations whilst working with others to ensure fast and yet high quality product.
2015 - 2016	Volunteer at School Library Volunteered at Brigshaw High School Library as part of my Duke of Edinburgh award. Involved working at the front desk answering student query's as well as stocking shelves.

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES & TECHNICAL SKILLS

PYTHON

I have over 6 years of experience in Python, it is the first language I learnt. I have used Python in many of my projects, namely in my A-Level project, E-book management software and my add-on to Nautilus (A popular Linux file explorer) to implement the creation of folders from templates.

HTML, CSS & JS

I have over 5 years of experience with web technologies, my A-Level project's user interface was created in Electron and made heavy use of HTML, CSS and especially JavaScript. Furthermore, I have my own Website.

- C# I learnt C# in my first year of university. I obtained a first in both modules that used C#. Programming & Data Structures as well as Algorithms & Complexity. I have also have a Microsoft Technical Associates (MTA) Certification in Software Development Fundamentals which tests C# knowledge, Object-Orientated Programming, general software development and more.
- C++ I learnt C++ in my second year of university, thanks to pre-reading and self-learning before the year I picked up the language quickly and assisted my peers who were struggling to grasp the language.

VERSION CONTROL

I have set up and managed a GitHub organisation with 7 members and was responsible for code reviews, pull requests and merges. I also use GitHub and version control for my personal projects.

MICROSOFT TECHNICAL ASSOCIATES (MTA) CERTIFICATIONS

Software Development Fundamentals

The software development fundamentals MTA tests core software development skills and tests other skills such as Databases, Desktop Applications, General Software Development, Object-oriented Programming and Web Applications. I achieved this certification on the 14th of January 2019.

Introduction to Programming Using Python

The Introduction to Programming Using Python MTA tests that the recipient is well versed in both the Python language but also critiacal skills needed for a software engirneer such as being able to doccument code to a high standered, and to be able to troubleshoot and error handle.

HOBBIES

I love the outdoors and walking, in my first year of University I was part of the Expedition society where I went on walks around Lincolnshire socialising with the other members and making some fast friends. When I'm not out walking I'm usually in the kitchen cooking, I love challenging myself to not just cook new dishes from recipe books but to develop my own.